Guide to the Marmaduke Rawdon, Commonplace Book
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Commonplace book]
1629-1632
OSBORN FB150
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.17
(1 volume)
Manuscript, in several unidentified hands, containing tracts on Parliament, verse, etc.
Rawdon, Marmaduke, Sir
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fb150. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Biography, English; English poetry -- 17th century; Trials -- England; Women authors; Great Britain -- Officials and employees; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1603-1649; Commonplace books; Bedford, Francis Russell, Earl of, 1593-1641; Charles, King of England, I, 1600-1649; Clare, John Holler, 1st earl of, 1564?-1637; Cotton, Robert, Sir, 1571-1631; Heath, Robert, Sir, 1575-1649; Rawdon, Marmaduke, Sir; Selden, John, 1584-1654; Carr, Robert, Earl of Somerset, -1645; St. John, Oliver, 1598?-1673; Vere, Francis, 1560-1609; England and Wales. Army; Great Britain. Parliament
- OSBORN fb150
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "A discourse of the High Court of Parliament, and of the authoritie of the same collected out of the common lawes of this land and other good authors", [early 17th c] (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      30 p.
      Anonymous manuscript.
      Great Britain. Parliament.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "A generall collection of all the offices of England, with the fees belonging to them", [early 17th c] (Box 1)
      48 p.
      Great Britain -- officials and
      employees.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. COURT OF STAR CHAMBER.
    - "A copie of the information exhibited in the Starr Chamber by Sir Robert Heath ... against ... Francis Earle of Bedford, Robert Earle of Somersett, John Earle of Clare, Sir Robert Cotton ... John Selden esq., Oliver St. John esq., Gilbert Barrett gent. & Richard James gent ... 1629", [ca. 1620] (Box 1)
      20 p.
      Contemporary MS copy.
      Bedford, Francis Russell, 4th earl
      of, 1593-1641; Somerset, Robert Carr,
      earl of, d. 1645; Clare, John Holler,
      1st earl of, 1564?-1637; Cotton, Sir
      Robert, 1st bart., 1571-1631; Selden,
      John, 1584-1654; St. John, Oliver,
      1598?-1673; Barrett, Gilbert; James,
      Richard.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "The true coppie of all the gentlemen bearing armes in the Artillarie Garden taken out of the Roule delivered to my Mr. Captayne Marmaduke Rawdon by Sir Geo. Whitmore then Lord Mayre", 1631 Dec 3 (Box 1)
      6 p.
      London. Honorable Artillery Company
      Great Britain -- military history
      Whitmore, Sir George, Lord Mayor of
      London, d. 1654.
  - VERE, SIR FRANCIS, 1560-1609
    - "The battle of Newport by Sr Francis Vere", [early 17th c] (Box 1)
      7 p.
      Contemporary MS copy, incomplete.
      Printed in Vere's "Commentaries"
      1657.
      Netherlands -- History -- Wars of
      Independence, 1556-1648; Nieuport,
      Battle of, 1600.
  - MOULSWORTH, MARTHA (DORSET) PRYNNE THROUGOOD, B. 1576
    - "The memorandum of Martha Moulsworth widdowe ... November the 10th 1632" (Box 1)
      3 p.
      An autobiographical poem. Martha
      Moulsworth was apparently the
      daughter of Robert Dorset (d. 1580),
      Canon of Christ Church.